# AYOBAMI **AJIBOLA**

No 12 Ini Bassey street Arab road Kubwa, Abuja, Nigeria · +234 8031957690 ayobamiajibola46@gmail.com · LinkedIn · GitHub · Portfolio

I'm a talented and enthusiastic developer with four years of experience identifying web-based user interactions, creating and implementing incredibly responsive user interface elements using react, and creating powerful Api using RESTful concept. I have extensive experience working with Javascript and its frameworks/libraries (Nodejs and Reactjs) and would welcome any opportunity to expand my skill set.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

JUNE 2021 - TILL DATE

# FULL STACK DEVELOPER, A'MOBI LTD

My major responsibilities at A'Mobi includes; designing and developing Api's, build UI and backend services for payment processing administration and management, define and document AWS best practices and strategies regarding application deployment and infrastructure maintenance

NOV 2019 – MARCH 2021 INTERN, A'MOBI LTD

Assisted developers in projects. Reviewed and tested new applications. Wrote documentations and design wireframe for web apps.

MARCH 2017 - OCT 2018

# FRONT END DEVELOPER, TEETYTECH

Developed and implemented front end architecture to support user interface concept, worked closely with the UI/UX designer to transform designs into code.

## **EDUCATION**

**NOVEMBER 2015** 

B.LIS, UNIVERSITY OF MAIDUGURI, BORNO STATE, NIGERIA

Bachelor of Library and Information Science

#### SKILLS

- NodeJS
- ReactJS
- Typescript
- REST API
- HTML/CSS

- PSQL
- Context Api
- MogoDB
- GIT
- Redux

# **ACTIVITIES**

Working in teams on various projects has given me the opportunity to improve my people and team building skills, I also collaborate with a Non-Governmental Organization (NGO) She ICT Society (SIS) to teach and make computer education applicable, easy, and free for young girls aged 8 to 16 in rural Abuja, Nigeria, with a mentorship program integrated for their self-development and growth.